footy.com 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy | FOOTY.COM

We use cookies to give you the best experience on our site. Continue or find out more.

This privacy policy explains how FOOTY.COM® collects personal information about you and how we use it.

### What information do we collect?

  * Your email address
  * That you are over 16
  * Your name
  * Your favourite team
  * Your IP address

### How do we collect the information?

  * From you directly when you fill in one of our forms (Your email address, that you are over 16, your favourite team)
  * From you directly when you respond to our emails asking for more information about you (Your name, Your favourite team)
  * From you when you visit one of our pages (Your IP address)

### What do we use the data we collect for?

  * We use your email address to communicate with you about deals and news that we think you might be interested in
  * We need to know you are over 16 years of age to ensure you are old enough for us to use your data
  * We use your name and favourite team to personalise the marketing emails you receive
  * We use your IP address to ensure that no malicious activity is performed on our website

### Marketing

If you have affirmatively consented to receive email communications from us, we will send you information about product deals and news that we feel you might be interested in. However, if you no longer wish to be contacted for marketing purposes then you can click the unsubscribe link that features in the footer of all emails we dispatch. 

Alternatively, please contact us and we will unsubscribe and/or purge your data from our system(s) manually on your behalf. We will never share your information with other companies for marketing purposes.

We use MailChimp as our Email Service Provider for sending email communications. MailChimp are fully ISO27001 compliant. For more detailed information on how MailChimp securely processes personal data, please read their [privacy policy](https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy/) and [security policy](https://mailchimp.com/about/security/).

### What are your rights under data protection law?

The law gives you certain rights in respect of the information that we hold about you. The website of the Information Commissioner’s Office ([http://www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/)) has a wealth of useful information in respect of your rights over your personal data.

### Access to your information and correction

You have the right to request a copy of the information that we hold about you. If you would like a copy of some or all of your personal information, please contact us.

We want to make sure that your personal information is accurate and up to date. You may ask us to correct or remove information you think is inaccurate. You can also ask for all information we hold about you to be removed.

If you wish to update or remove your data please contact us.

### Cookies

Cookies are text files placed on your computer to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information. This information is used to track visitor use of our website and to compile statistical reports on website activity. We **do not** use cookies to personally identify you.

You can exercise your preferences about what cookies are served on our website by visiting the TRUSTe preference center which is accessible via <http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/>.

You can also set your browser to not accept cookies via native browser functionality, however, in a few cases some of our website features may not function as a result and your experience will be affected. 

For more detailed information please read our cookie policy.

### Analytics

We use Google Analytics to monitor the usage of our website to provide insight into which parts of our website are being used and how users interact with it. We use IP anonymization within Google Analytics so that a user’s full IP is never stored.

### Notifications

We use OneSignal to collect, manage and send push notifications to users. Notifications are only sent to users that have explicitly chosen to receive them. If you have opted in to receive push notifications and no longer want to receive notifications you can turn them off through their browser settings. If you want to find out more on how your data is used you can read [OneSignal's privacy policy](https://onesignal.com/privacy_policy).

### Affiliates and other websites

Our website contains links to other websites. This privacy policy only applies to this website so when you link to other websites you should read their own privacy policies.

Some of the links on our website go to affiliate websites that reward us with commission when a user completes a sale. When a sale is completed we receive information about the sale but not personal data about you.

If you would like to know more about the privacy policies of the individual affiliate networks we work with then follow the relevant link below.

### Changes to our privacy policy

We keep our privacy policy under regular review and we will place any updates on this web page. This privacy policy was last updated on 05/12/2018.

### How to contact us

If you wish to contact us about our privacy policy or the information we hold about you then please contact us.
